final List<Map<String, dynamic>> meiosis = [
  {
    "Meiosis": {
      "description": "Meiosis",
      "marks": 30,
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is the purpose of meiosis in organisms?",
          "options": [
            "Growth and repair",
            "Production of gametes",
            "Asexual reproduction",
            "Energy production"
          ],
          "answer": "Production of gametes"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "How many daughter cells are produced at the end of meiosis?",
          "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"],
          "answer": "4"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many cell divisions occur in meiosis?",
          "options": ["One", "Two", "Three", "Four"],
          "answer": "Two"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which phase of meiosis involves crossing over?",
          "options": [
            "Prophase I",
            "Metaphase I",
            "Anaphase II",
            "Telophase II"
          ],
          "answer": "Prophase I"
        },
        {
          "question": "During which stage do homologous chromosomes separate?",
          "options": ["Anaphase I", "Anaphase II", "Prophase I", "Telophase I"],
          "answer": "Anaphase I"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is a result of meiosis?",
          "options": [
            "Genetically identical cells",
            "Genetically different cells",
            "Increase in chromosome number",
            "No change in chromosome number"
          ],
          "answer": "Genetically different cells"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the chromosome number in human gametes after meiosis?",
          "options": ["23", "46", "69", "92"],
          "answer": "23"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the main difference between meiosis I and meiosis II?",
          "options": [
            "Meiosis I reduces chromosome number; Meiosis II separates chromatids",
            "Meiosis I separates chromatids; Meiosis II reduces chromosome number",
            "Both meiosis I and II reduce chromosome number",
            "Both meiosis I and II separate chromatids"
          ],
          "answer":
              "Meiosis I reduces chromosome number; Meiosis II separates chromatids"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which structure holds homologous chromosomes together during crossing over?",
          "options": ["Centrosome", "Chiasma", "Spindle fiber", "Chromatid"],
          "answer": "Chiasma"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which of the following statements about meiosis is true?",
          "options": [
            "It occurs in somatic cells",
            "It results in identical daughter cells",
            "It increases genetic variation",
            "It maintains the diploid chromosome number"
          ],
          "answer": "It increases genetic variation"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
];

final List<Map<String, dynamic>> reproduction_in_vertebrates = [
  {
    "Reproduction in Vertebrates": {
      "description": "Reproduction in Vertebrates",
      "marks": 30,
      "questions": [
        {
          "question":
              "What type of fertilization occurs in most fish and amphibians?",
          "options": [
            "Internal fertilization",
            "External fertilization",
            "Asexual reproduction",
            "Parthenogenesis"
          ],
          "answer": "External fertilization"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which vertebrate group has the most parental care?",
          "options": ["Fish", "Amphibians", "Reptiles", "Mammals"],
          "answer": "Mammals"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the function of the amniotic egg in reptiles and birds?",
          "options": [
            "Provide nutrients",
            "Protect embryo from dehydration",
            "Facilitate external fertilization",
            "Enable metamorphosis"
          ],
          "answer": "Protect embryo from dehydration"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which reproductive strategy involves giving birth to live young?",
          "options": [
            "Oviparous",
            "Viviparous",
            "Ovoviviparous",
            "Parthenogenesis"
          ],
          "answer": "Viviparous"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which hormone is primarily responsible for inducing labor in mammals?",
          "options": ["Estrogen", "Progesterone", "Oxytocin", "Testosterone"],
          "answer": "Oxytocin"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which vertebrate class has the highest diversity of reproductive modes?",
          "options": ["Mammals", "Reptiles", "Amphibians", "Birds"],
          "answer": "Amphibians"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the main advantage of internal fertilization over external fertilization?",
          "options": [
            "Higher chance of fertilization",
            "More offspring",
            "Less energy required",
            "Faster development"
          ],
          "answer": "Higher chance of fertilization"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which vertebrate group primarily reproduces through oviparity?",
          "options": ["Birds", "Mammals", "Amphibians", "Fish"],
          "answer": "Birds"
        },
        {
          "question": "In which vertebrate group do marsupials belong?",
          "options": ["Reptiles", "Amphibians", "Mammals", "Fish"],
          "answer": "Mammals"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which term describes animals that lay eggs with little or no embryonic development inside the mother?",
          "options": ["Ovoviviparous", "Viviparous", "Oviparous", "Placental"],
          "answer": "Oviparous"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
];

final List<Map<String, dynamic>> human_reproduction = [
  {
    "Human Reproduction": {
      "description": "Human Reproduction Questions",
      "marks": 30,
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is the primary male reproductive organ?",
          "options": ["Testes", "Ovaries", "Prostate gland", "Uterus"],
          "answer": "Testes"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which hormone regulates the menstrual cycle?",
          "options": ["Insulin", "Testosterone", "Estrogen", "Adrenaline"],
          "answer": "Estrogen"
        },
        {
          "question": "Where does fertilization usually take place in humans?",
          "options": ["Ovary", "Uterus", "Fallopian tube", "Vagina"],
          "answer": "Fallopian tube"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which structure in the male reproductive system stores and transports sperm?",
          "options": [
            "Testes",
            "Epididymis",
            "Vas deferens",
            "Seminal vesicle"
          ],
          "answer": "Vas deferens"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which part of the female reproductive system is responsible for housing a developing fetus?",
          "options": ["Ovary", "Fallopian tube", "Uterus", "Cervix"],
          "answer": "Uterus"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the term for the release of an egg from the ovary?",
          "options": [
            "Menstruation",
            "Ovulation",
            "Fertilization",
            "Implantation"
          ],
          "answer": "Ovulation"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which male reproductive gland produces the majority of seminal fluid?",
          "options": [
            "Prostate gland",
            "Seminal vesicles",
            "Cowper's gland",
            "Testes"
          ],
          "answer": "Seminal vesicles"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the name of the organ where sperm cells are produced?",
          "options": ["Penis", "Epididymis", "Testes", "Prostate gland"],
          "answer": "Testes"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which hormone is responsible for male secondary sexual characteristics?",
          "options": ["Estrogen", "Progesterone", "Testosterone", "Oxytocin"],
          "answer": "Testosterone"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the term for the process in which a fertilized egg implants into the uterus lining?",
          "options": [
            "Ovulation",
            "Fertilization",
            "Implantation",
            "Menstruation"
          ],
          "answer": "Implantation"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
];

final List<Map<String, dynamic>> responding_to_the_environment_humans = [
  {
    "Responding to the Environment (Humans)": {
      "description": "Responding to the Environment (Humans)",
      "marks": 30,
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Which part of the brain controls voluntary movements?",
          "options": [
            "Cerebellum",
            "Medulla oblongata",
            "Cerebrum",
            "Hypothalamus"
          ],
          "answer": "Cerebrum"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the function of the medulla oblongata?",
          "options": [
            "Regulates breathing and heart rate",
            "Controls voluntary movement",
            "Processes sensory information",
            "Produces hormones"
          ],
          "answer": "Regulates breathing and heart rate"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which part of the nervous system is responsible for reflex actions?",
          "options": ["Brain", "Spinal cord", "Cerebellum", "Hypothalamus"],
          "answer": "Spinal cord"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the function of the autonomic nervous system?",
          "options": [
            "Controls involuntary actions",
            "Processes conscious thoughts",
            "Regulates blood sugar levels",
            "Produces hormones"
          ],
          "answer": "Controls involuntary actions"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which part of the eye controls the amount of light entering?",
          "options": ["Retina", "Lens", "Iris", "Cornea"],
          "answer": "Iris"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which type of neuron transmits impulses from receptors to the central nervous system?",
          "options": [
            "Motor neuron",
            "Sensory neuron",
            "Interneuron",
            "Relay neuron"
          ],
          "answer": "Sensory neuron"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which structure in the ear helps maintain balance?",
          "options": [
            "Cochlea",
            "Eardrum",
            "Semicircular canals",
            "Auditory nerve"
          ],
          "answer": "Semicircular canals"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which gland is responsible for regulating metabolism?",
          "options": [
            "Adrenal gland",
            "Thyroid gland",
            "Pituitary gland",
            "Pancreas"
          ],
          "answer": "Thyroid gland"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the function of neurotransmitters in the nervous system?",
          "options": [
            "Transmit signals across synapses",
            "Generate electrical impulses",
            "Regulate blood pressure",
            "Store genetic information"
          ],
          "answer": "Transmit signals across synapses"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which part of the nervous system is responsible for the fight-or-flight response?",
          "options": [
            "Somatic nervous system",
            "Sympathetic nervous system",
            "Parasympathetic nervous system",
            "Central nervous system"
          ],
          "answer": "Sympathetic nervous system"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
];

final List<Map<String, dynamic>> human_endocrine_system = [
  {
    "Human Endocrine System": {
      "description": "Human Endocrine System Questions",
      "marks": 30,
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Which gland is known as the master gland?",
          "options": [
            "Thyroid gland",
            "Adrenal gland",
            "Pituitary gland",
            "Pancreas"
          ],
          "answer": "Pituitary gland"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which hormone regulates blood sugar levels?",
          "options": ["Adrenaline", "Insulin", "Thyroxine", "Glucagon"],
          "answer": "Insulin"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the main function of the thyroid gland?",
          "options": [
            "Regulate metabolism",
            "Control blood pressure",
            "Digest food",
            "Filter toxins"
          ],
          "answer": "Regulate metabolism"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which gland produces adrenaline?",
          "options": [
            "Pancreas",
            "Pituitary gland",
            "Adrenal gland",
            "Thyroid gland"
          ],
          "answer": "Adrenal gland"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which hormone is responsible for the fight-or-flight response?",
          "options": ["Insulin", "Adrenaline", "Estrogen", "Melatonin"],
          "answer": "Adrenaline"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which hormone controls water balance in the body?",
          "options": ["Oxytocin", "Vasopressin", "Insulin", "Testosterone"],
          "answer": "Vasopressin"
        },
        {
          "question": "Where is the hormone melatonin produced?",
          "options": ["Thyroid gland", "Pineal gland", "Pancreas", "Ovary"],
          "answer": "Pineal gland"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which hormone plays a major role in the regulation of calcium levels?",
          "options": ["Insulin", "Parathyroid hormone", "Glucagon", "Estrogen"],
          "answer": "Parathyroid hormone"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What hormone is responsible for stimulating milk production in females?",
          "options": ["Progesterone", "Prolactin", "Testosterone", "Oxytocin"],
          "answer": "Prolactin"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which hormone is responsible for regulating sleep patterns?",
          "options": ["Melatonin", "Cortisol", "Thyroxine", "Glucagon"],
          "answer": "Melatonin"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
];

final List<Map<String, dynamic>> homeostasis_in_humans = [
  {
    "Homeostasis in Humans": {
      "description": "Homeostasis in Humans",
      "marks": 30,
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is homeostasis?",
          "options": [
            "The process of producing energy",
            "The maintenance of a stable internal environment",
            "The breakdown of food in the digestive system",
            "The transportation of oxygen in the blood"
          ],
          "answer": "The maintenance of a stable internal environment"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which organ is primarily responsible for regulating blood glucose levels?",
          "options": ["Liver", "Pancreas", "Kidneys", "Stomach"],
          "answer": "Pancreas"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which hormone lowers blood glucose levels?",
          "options": ["Glucagon", "Insulin", "Adrenaline", "Cortisol"],
          "answer": "Insulin"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which part of the brain regulates body temperature?",
          "options": [
            "Cerebellum",
            "Medulla oblongata",
            "Hypothalamus",
            "Cerebrum"
          ],
          "answer": "Hypothalamus"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the primary function of the kidneys in homeostasis?",
          "options": [
            "Produce red blood cells",
            "Filter and regulate water and ion balance",
            "Break down toxins in the blood",
            "Help with digestion"
          ],
          "answer": "Filter and regulate water and ion balance"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "How does the body respond to an increase in temperature?",
          "options": [
            "Shivering and increased metabolism",
            "Sweating and vasodilation",
            "Constriction of blood vessels",
            "Decreased breathing rate"
          ],
          "answer": "Sweating and vasodilation"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which organ plays a key role in regulating water balance?",
          "options": ["Lungs", "Heart", "Kidneys", "Liver"],
          "answer": "Kidneys"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What is the function of ADH (Antidiuretic Hormone) in homeostasis?",
          "options": [
            "Increases urine production",
            "Stimulates digestion",
            "Reduces water loss by the kidneys",
            "Increases glucose absorption"
          ],
          "answer": "Reduces water loss by the kidneys"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which condition results from the failure of homeostasis in blood glucose regulation?",
          "options": [
            "Hypertension",
            "Diabetes mellitus",
            "Osteoporosis",
            "Asthma"
          ],
          "answer": "Diabetes mellitus"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "How does the body respond when blood glucose levels are too low?",
          "options": [
            "The pancreas releases insulin",
            "The liver releases glucagon",
            "The kidneys release ADH",
            "The stomach releases bile"
          ],
          "answer": "The liver releases glucagon"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
];

final List<Map<String, dynamic>> responding_to_the_environment_plants = [
  {
    "Responding to the Environment (Plants)": {
      "description": "Responding to the Environment (Plants)",
      "marks": 30,
      "questions": [
        {
          "question":
              "What is the primary hormone responsible for phototropism in plants?",
          "options": ["Gibberellin", "Cytokinin", "Auxin", "Abscisic Acid"],
          "answer": "Auxin"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which plant movement is a response to touch?",
          "options": [
            "Phototropism",
            "Thigmotropism",
            "Gravitropism",
            "Hydrotropism"
          ],
          "answer": "Thigmotropism"
        },
        {
          "question": "What part of the plant detects light for phototropism?",
          "options": ["Roots", "Stem", "Leaves", "Shoot tip"],
          "answer": "Shoot tip"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which hormone promotes seed dormancy in plants?",
          "options": ["Auxin", "Gibberellin", "Abscisic Acid", "Cytokinin"],
          "answer": "Abscisic Acid"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What type of tropism causes roots to grow downward in response to gravity?",
          "options": [
            "Phototropism",
            "Geotropism",
            "Thigmotropism",
            "Hydrotropism"
          ],
          "answer": "Geotropism"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which plant hormone is responsible for fruit ripening?",
          "options": ["Gibberellin", "Cytokinin", "Ethylene", "Abscisic Acid"],
          "answer": "Ethylene"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "What type of tropism allows plants to grow towards a water source?",
          "options": [
            "Geotropism",
            "Hydrotropism",
            "Thigmotropism",
            "Phototropism"
          ],
          "answer": "Hydrotropism"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which of the following is an example of a nastic movement?",
          "options": [
            "A sunflower turning towards the sun",
            "A vine coiling around a support",
            "A Mimosa plant closing its leaves when touched",
            "Roots growing towards water"
          ],
          "answer": "A Mimosa plant closing its leaves when touched"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which plant hormone stimulates cell division and is important for growth?",
          "options": ["Gibberellin", "Cytokinin", "Auxin", "Ethylene"],
          "answer": "Cytokinin"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which plant response helps it avoid drought conditions?",
          "options": [
            "Leaf wilting",
            "Stomatal closure",
            "Thigmotropism",
            "Hydrotropism"
          ],
          "answer": "Stomatal closure"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
];

final List<Map<String, dynamic>> human_impact_on_environment = [
  {
    "Human Impact on Environment": {
      "description": "Human Impact on Environment",
      "marks": 20,
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is the main cause of global warming?",
          "options": [
            "Deforestation",
            "Greenhouse gas emissions",
            "Overfishing",
            "Water pollution"
          ],
          "answer": "Greenhouse gas emissions"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which human activity is the leading cause of deforestation?",
          "options": ["Mining", "Agriculture", "Urbanization", "Logging"],
          "answer": "Agriculture"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "How does eutrophication negatively impact aquatic ecosystems?",
          "options": [
            "Increases oxygen levels",
            "Causes excessive algae growth",
            "Improves water quality",
            "Reduces fish population growth"
          ],
          "answer": "Causes excessive algae growth"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is a renewable energy source?",
          "options": ["Coal", "Nuclear power", "Solar energy", "Natural gas"],
          "answer": "Solar energy"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the primary reason for biodiversity loss?",
          "options": [
            "Climate change",
            "Poaching",
            "Habitat destruction",
            "Introduction of new species"
          ],
          "answer": "Habitat destruction"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which practice helps to reduce soil erosion?",
          "options": [
            "Deforestation",
            "Crop rotation",
            "Overgrazing",
            "Urbanization"
          ],
          "answer": "Crop rotation"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the impact of acid rain on the environment?",
          "options": [
            "Increases crop yields",
            "Improves soil quality",
            "Damages aquatic life and forests",
            "Reduces air pollution"
          ],
          "answer": "Damages aquatic life and forests"
        },
        {
          "question":
              "Which gas is most responsible for ozone layer depletion?",
          "options": [
            "Carbon dioxide",
            "Methane",
            "Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs)",
            "Sulfur dioxide"
          ],
          "answer": "Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs)"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the main goal of sustainable development?",
          "options": [
            "Increase industrial production",
            "Meet current needs without harming future generations",
            "Maximize the use of natural resources",
            "Expand urban areas"
          ],
          "answer": "Meet current needs without harming future generations"
        },
        {
          "question": "How does deforestation contribute to climate change?",
          "options": [
            "Reduces oxygen levels",
            "Increases carbon dioxide in the atmosphere",
            "Increases the ozone layer thickness",
            "Decreases water pollution"
          ],
          "answer": "Increases carbon dioxide in the atmosphere"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
];
